Tanvir Hossain

33-37 Parliament Road, Macquarie Fields, NSW, 2564 Ph: 0404643188

Email: hossaintanvir@live.co.uk, GitHub: https://github.com/thossain89 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thossain89/

Professional Summary

I am a solutions-driven Full Stack Developer applying Engineering background and strong technical skillset towards building functional websites and web applications. I have graduated in Electrical and Electronics Engineering and have a Web Development certificate from University of Sydney (USYD), where I have developed skills in HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Moment.js, Node.js and responsive web design. My strengths include problem solving, project management, and agile adaptation to last minute support changes, which makes me an integral member of any team

Skills

- Excellent Communication Skills and time management
- Effective leadership and management
- Research, planning and execution
- Agile adaptation to last minute changes.
- Experienced in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, and responsive web development
- Proficient in MATLAB, LabView, Proteus and MS office suits
- Apt knowledge in windows and Mac workstation hardware
- Experienced in using variety of operating systems

Experience

Sales Specialist Anaconda Mar 2015 - Current Kensington, NSW

- The current role covers multiple departments within the business, primarily managing inventory, online orders, warranty claims and IT related issues.
- Skilled user of SAP inventory management software and SWIFT (ecommerce) platform.
- Troubleshoot IT related problems in store, for example, PDA, POS, workstations, communication radios and security cameras.
- Remote support other NSW stores to troubleshoot SAP.
- Supervise ecommerce team, to ensure adherence to quality standards, deadlines, and proper procedures, correcting errors or problems.
- Maintain records pertaining to inventory, personnel, orders, supplies, or machine maintenance.
- Implement corporate or departmental policies, procedures, and service standards in conjunction with management regarding warranty claims.
- Resolve customer complaints or answer customers' questions regarding products, policies and warranty procedures.
- Lead the team in absence of store manager

Teacher Private Tuition

Jan 2013 - Dec 2014 Uttara, Dhaka Bangladesh

- Instruct through lectures, discussions, and demonstrations in one or more subjects, such as Mathematics, Physics or Chemistry.
- Modify the general education curriculum for special-needs students based upon a variety of instructional techniques and instructional technology.
- Prepare materials according to students' need.
- Establish clear objectives for all lessons, units, and projects and communicate those objectives to students.
- Confer with parents or guardians, other teachers, counselors, and administrators to resolve students' behavioral and academic problems.
- Guide and counsel students with academic problems, or special academic interests.
- Teach students personal development skills such as goal setting, independence, and self-advocacy.
- Use computers, audio-visual aids, and other equipment and materials to supplement presentations.

Sales Team Member Harrods (Case Luggage)

Jun 2010 – Aug 2011 Kensington, London UK

Jul 2012

- Stock push on the floor according to the morning floor check data.
- Packing online/Telephone orders with fast and efficient way.
- Floor walk with team leaders and list the items for next day replenishment
- Help customers with travel accessories and provide them with information regarding travel goods.

Education

BSc Electrical and Electronics Engineering Plymouth University Plymouth, England Graduated with second class honors upper limit (2.1)

HND (Higher National Diploma) in Electrical/Electronic Engineering Sep 2011 (Communication) Greater London, England ICON College of Technology and Management

GCE (General Certificate of Education, Edexcel) Jun 2008 Millennium Dhaka, Bangladesh Mathematics (B), Physics (C), Chemistry (D)

Reference

Reference can be provided on request.

Graduated with 8 distinctions, 4 merits and 4 passes